Inventory of the Edward Ellis Smith papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- M. G. Voronova, Izoblichennye provokatory, Petrograd: gazetno-zhurnalnaya knizhnaya ekspeditsiya, 1917 (Box-folder 17: 9)
- Department of police headquarters, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 17: 10)
- "History of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, Bolsheviks, Short Course,", 1938 (Box-folder 17: 11)
- History of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, 1960 (Box-folder 17: 12)
- Haywood, "Big Bill," from Dulles' book, 1968 August 8 (Box-folder 17: 13)
- Gorky, Maxim, Days with Lenin, 1932 (Box-folder 17: 14)
- "Iz zhizni i deatelnosti obshchestva, obshchee sobranie chlenov 15-go fevralya," Edinstvo, no. 2, 1909 March 2 (Box-folder 17: 15)
- "K delu malinovskago," Dyen, no. 90, p. 1, 1917 June 21 (Box-folder 17: 16)
- "K otstavke Malinovskago," Russkaya Vedomosti, no. 110, p. 4, 1914 May 14 (Box-folder 17: 17)
- "K ukhodv Malinovskago," Metallist, no. 8 (45), 1914 June 12 (Box-folder 17: 18)
- "K ukhodu Malinovskago," Russkaya Vedomosti, no. 113, 1914 May 18 (Box-folder 17: 19)
- "Razsledovanie obvinenii protiv Malinovskogo," Russkiya Vedomosti, no. 121, 1914 May 28 (Box-folder 17: 20)
- Kamenev, L. B., Leninskii Sbornik, excerpts, 1925 (Box-folder 17: 21)
- Kamenev, V., "Zanyatie deprtamenta politsii," Golos minuvshego na chuzhoi storone, 1917 March (Box-folder 17: 22)
- Kelson, Zigfrid, "Militsiya fevralskoi revoliutsii - vozrozhdenie okhranki," Byloe, no. 5 (33), Leningrad, 1925 (Box-folder 17: 23)
- Khonyavko, I. P., "V podpolye i v emigratsii parizhskaya sektsiya bolshevikov do nochalo,", 1911-1917 (Box-folder 17: 24)
- "Khronika Gosudarstvennaya Duma," Strakhovanie Rabochikh, no. 2, 1913 (Box-folder 17: 25)
- Kiselev, M., "Preparation for a Party Conference and a Trip Abroad in July 1914," Proletarskaia Revoliutsiia, 1924 (Box-folder 17: 26)
- Komissarov, agent, 1917 (Box-folder 17: 27)
- Khorbut, M., "Strakhovaya kampaniya,", 1912-1914 (Box-folder 17: 28)
- "N. V. Krylenko, "Entsiklopedichesky slovar russkogo bibliograficheskogo," Mockba, undated (Box-folder 17: 29)
- Beletskago, S. P., "Iz vospominaniy," Kpasnaia Ietopis, no. 2, 1924 (Box-folder 17: 30)
- "Agonia menshevizma," Edinstvo, no. 155, 1917 October 4 (Box-folder 17: 31)
- Degot, V., Pod znamenem bolshevisma, selected excerpts, 1927 (Box-folder 17: 32)
- Bobrovskaya, C., "Twenty Years in Underground Russia: Memoirs of a Rank-and-File Bolshevik," London: Lawrence, 1934 (Box-folder 17: 33)
- Beletsky, "Kommissar svidensky i beletsky," Novoye Vedemosti, 1918 May 9 (Box-folder 17: 34)
- "Burglar Sat in Duma - Spy and Organizer of Crime Served Police and Revolutionaries," The New York Times, 1917 August 13 (Box-folder 17: 35)
- Bourtzev, Vladimir, "Lenine and Malinovsky," Struggling Russia, 1919 May 17 (Box-folder 17: 36)
- Cherepakhov, "Russkaya periodicheskaya pechati," M. S. edition, Moscow, 1957 (Box-folder 17: 37)
- Comparative Pay Scales for U.S. Congress and 4th Duma, 1968 (Box-folder 17: 38)
- Bosh, O., "Prazhkaya konferentsiya," Proletarskaya Revolutsiya, 1925 (Box-folder 17: 39)
- Bukharin, "In Memory of Ilich M.," Pravda, 1925 January 21 (Box-folder 17: 40)
- Beletsky, "Khodataistvo ob osvobozhdenii beletskago," Novye, 1918 (Box-folder 17: 41)
- "Delo Malinovskogo iz soobshcheniya ministra yustitsii," Rech, 1914 June 17 (Box-folder 17: 42)
- "Delo Malinovskogo," Rech, no. 139, 1917 June 6 (Box-folder 17: 43)
- "Delo Malinovskogo," Dyen, no. 92, p. 2, 1917 June 23 (Box-folder 17: 44)
- "Delo Malinovskogo," Russkoe Slovo, no. 121, p. 3, 1917 May 31 (Box-folder 17: 45)
- "Delo Malinovskogo," Russkoe Slovo no. 132, p. 3, 1917 June 13 (Box-folder 17: 46)
- "Delo Malinovskogo, po materialam sledstvennoi kommissii," Russkoe Slovo, no. 135, p. 2, 1917 June 16 (Box-folder 17: 47)
- "Departament politsii i raskol R.S.-D.R.P.," Rabochaya Gazeta, no. 19, p. 1-2, 1917 March 29 (Box-folder 17: 48)
- "Dubinsky mukhadze," Ordzhonikidze, 1968 September 21 (Box-folder 17: 49)
- Padenie, vol. III, 1925 (Box-folder 17: 50)
- Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box-folder 17: 51)
- "Malinovsky prigovoren k rasstrelu,", 1968 (Box-folder 17: 52)
- "Delo provokatore Malinovskogo," Severnaya Kommuna, no. 146, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 17: 53)
- Znamia Trudovoi Kommuny, no. 54, 1918 October 25 (Box-folder 17: 54)
- Police reports and Edinstvo article, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 17: 55)
- "Lenin V. I.," Sochineniia, vol. XX, 1917 (Box-folder 17: 56)
- "Maksakov, ternii 'nashego puti', Iz epokhi zvezdy i," Pravda, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 17: 57)
- "Iz zhizni i deatelnosti obshchestva," Edinstvo, no. 10, p. 9-12, 1909 October 22 (Box-folder 17: 58)
- "Iz zhizni i deatelnosti obshchestva," Edinstvo, no. 6, 1909 June 15 (Box-folder 17: 59)
- Advertisement of Malinovsky's speech in Paris, the Nicolaevsky collection, Hoover Institution, 1914 January 20 (Box-folder 17: 60)
- Map of Malinovsky's residence locations, St. Petersburg, 1912 (Box-folder 17: 61)
- "Po rossii," Nash Put, 1910 July 15 (Box-folder 17: 62)
- "K voprosu ob obshchestvennykh," Edinstvo, no. 7, 1909 July 10 (Box-folder 17: 63)
- "Iz zhizni i deatelnosti obshchestva" Edinstvo, no. 1, p. 15-17, 1909 February 10 (Box-folder 17: 64)
- Malinovsky Speeches IV, Duma, session I, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 17: 65)
- Loose materials, 1968 (Box-folder 17: 66)
  Includes typed excerpts from publications about the Soviet Union during World War II and research notes regarding Roman Malinovsky.
- "Iz vospominanii Mikhail Rodzianko. 1914-1917 g.g.," Bylof, no. 21, Petrograd, 1923 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- Loginov, V. T., V. N. Stepanov, and Z. N. Tikhonova, "Adresnaya kniga," Istoricheskii Arkiiv, 1959 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- Loginov, V. T., "Adresnye knigi TsK RSDRP," Istoricheskii Arkhiv, 1912-1917 (Box-folder 18: 3)
- Malinovsky Speeches IV, Duma, session II, 1913-1914 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- "From the Minister of Justice," Vestnik of Provisional Government, no. 81, 1917 July 16 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- Nasha Zaria, no. 10-11, 1913 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- "Sobranie 31 yanvarya v zale," Edinstvo, no. 13, 1910 (Box-folder 18: 7)
- Martov, "Terror and Provocation,", undated (Box-folder 18: 8)
- Research and notes, related to Malinovsky, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 18: 9)
- Medvedev, M., "Provokatsiya," Pravda, no. 20, 1917 March 29 (Box-folder 18: 10)
- Metallist, no. 2, 1914 February 4 (Box-folder 18: 11)
- Mitrevich, A. A., "Vospominania o rabochem revoliutsionnom dvizhenii," Proletarskaya Revoliutsiya, no. 4, 1922 (Box-folder 18: 12)
- Moskalev, "Biuro tsentralnogo" Komiteta RSDRP v Rossii, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 13)
- Muranov, M., "Fakticheskaya spravka," Pravda, no. 8, 1917 March 14 (Box-folder 18: 14)
- "Mysl," Mockba, no. 1-3, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 18: 15)
- "Otchet o zasedaniyakh Rossiiskoi," Sotsialdemokrat, no. 25, 1911 December 8 (Box-folder 18: 16)
- "Krainie levye v gosudarstvennoi dume," Severnye Zapiski, 1914 (Box-folder 18: 17)
- N. R., "Nikolai II po departamentu politsii," Katorgai Ssylka, 1926 (Box-folder 18: 18)
- "Ne imeya shistago, printsipialnago, oruzhiya, oni, khvatayutsya za gryaznoe," Pravda, no. 68, p. 3, 1917 June 10 (Box-folder 18: 19)
- "Yu kamenev," Edinstvo, no. 113, p. 4, 1917 August 11 (Box-folder 18: 20)
- "Zapreshchenie lekstii deputatov," Strakhouanie Rabochikh, no. 6, 1913 May (Box-folder 18: 21)
- "Zasedanie TsK RSDRP 15-15 aprelya '14," Voprosy Istorii KPSS, no. 4, 1957 (Box-folder 18: 22)
- Zavadsky, S. V., "Na velikom izlome," Arkhiv Russkoi Revoliutsii, 1923 (Box-folder 18: 23)
- "Zayavlenie s.-d. rabochei fraktsii gosudarstvennoi dumy," Russkiya Vedomosti, no. 107, p. 2, 1914 May 10 (Box-folder 18: 24)
- "Zhitomirsky from pyatnitsky," Zapiski Bolshevika, no. 136, 1913 (Box-folder 18: 25)
- "Zhitomirsky," Russkoe Slovo, no. 136, p. 2, 1917 June 17 (Box-folder 18: 26)
- Zinoviev, G., "Gosudarstvennoe izdatelsvo," God Revoliutsii, 1925 (Box-folder 18: 27)
- Zinoviev, G., "Rossiiskoi kommunisticheskoi partii bol'shevikov," Istoriya, 1924 (Box-folder 18: 28)
- Trotsky, L., Sochineniya, Moscow, 1926 (Box-folder 18: 29)
- Lipkin, Ark, "Nakanune protsessa bolshevistskoi frakstii IV gosudarstvennoi," Katorga i Ssylka, no. 30, 1927 (Box-folder 18: 30)
- Material for Stalin galleys, 1967 (Box-folder 18: 31)
- "Iz zhizn and sobranie v sale," Edinstvo, no. 3, p. 6-9, 1909 March 19 (Box-folder 18: 32)
- "Lenin V. I.," Sochineniia, ed. III, undated (Box-folder 18: 33)
- "Lenin V. I.," Sochineniia, ed. IV, undated (Box-folder 18: 34)
- Lenin, N., "Strannoe izvrashchenie tsitat," Pravda, 1917 June 30 (Box-folder 18: 35)
- "Novye dokumenty V. I. Lenina," Istoricheskii Arkhiv, no. 2, 1960 March-April (Box-folder 18: 36)
- Lenin, N., Leninsky Sbornik, vol. II, 1925 (Box-folder 18: 37)
- "Novye dokumenty V. I. Lenina," Istorichesky Arkhiv, no. IV, 1959 (Box-folder 18: 38)
- "Lenin, V. I.," Sochineniia, ed. III and IV, undated (Box-folder 18: 39)
- Andrei, "Gazete vperod," Sotsial-Demokrat, no. 69, p.3, 1917 May 31 (Box-folder 18: 40)
- Andrei, "Travlya bolshevikov," Sotsial-Demokrat, no. 66, 1917 May 27 (Box-folder 18: 41)
- "R. V. Malinovsky," Metallist, no. 23, p. 11, 1912 November 10 (Box-folder 18: 42)
- Prologue, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 18: 43)
- "Okhrana otdel establishment of circular no. 1401 of M.V.D.," Interior Police Department, 1903 (Box-folder 18: 44)
- Levine, Isaac D., Stalin's Great Secret, p. 22, 1956 (Box-folder 18: 45)
- Introduction, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 46)
- Reel index, the Menshevik collection of newspapers, periodicals, pamphlets and books, undated (Box-folder 18: 47)
- Loose materials, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 48)
  Includes a typed essay, resume, and letters of correspondence from William S. Heiliger, as well as photocopies of documents published by the Okhrana.
- Rodzianko, M. V., "Iz vospominanii," Byloe, no. 21, 1923 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- "Spisok provokatorov," Rech, no. 82, 1917 April 9 (Box-folder 19: 2)
- "Pismo malinovskago ministru yustitsii," Rech, no. 184, p. 4, 1917 August 8 (Box-folder 19: 3)
- "Ot komendanta okhrannago otdeleniya, pismo v redaktsiyu," Rech, no. 84, p. 7, 1917 April 12 (Box-folder 19: 4)
- Arkatov, E., "Smert sergei degaeva," Novye Vedomosti, 1918 April 25 (Box-folder 19: 5)
- Arkhivnoe Delo, vyp 13, 1927 (Box-folder 19: 6)
- "Arest Dzhunkovskogo iz Moskvy po telefonu," Krasnaya Gazeta, 1918 September 20 (Box-folder 19: 7)
- Byloe, no. 29, Petrograd, 1918 (Box-folder 19: 8)
- "A. E. Badaev," Pravda, no. 308, p. 4, 1951 November 4 (Box-folder 19: 9)
- Badaev, M., "Novaia seriia," Byloe, p. 70, 1926 (Box-folder 19: 10)
- "Memories of Bakai," Byloe, 1908 (Box-folder 19: 11)
- Demyam, Bedny, "Election Poems," Pravda, 1917 June 10 (Box-folder 19: 12)
- Demyam, Bedny, "Gospodam klebetnikam iz burzhuaznykh gazet," Pravda, 1917 (Box-folder 19: 13)
- Beletsky, S. P., "Delo beletskago," Novye Vedomosti, no. 63, 1918 May 7 (Box-folder 19: 14)
- Beletsky, S. P., "Grigory Rasputin iz Vospominani," Byloe, no. 20-23, Petrograd, 1923 (Box-folder 19: 15)
- Tsiavlovsky, M., "Moskovskaya Okhrana v 1915," Golos Minurshago, p. 251, 1918 (Box-folder 19: 16)
- "Troyanovsky arrest," Novye Vedomosti, p. 4, 1918 June 15 (Box-folder 19: 17)
- Trotskii, L., "Politicheskaya khronika," Sochineniia, vol. 4, 1926 (Box-folder 19: 18)
- Trotskii, L., Sochineniia, vol. 3, part 1, Moscow, 1917 (Box-folder 19: 19)
- "Interrogation of I. M. Zolotarev on June 2, 1917," Padenie, vol. V, 1926 (Box-folder 19: 20)
- "Perepiska TsK RSDRP mestnymi," Istorichesky Arkhiv no. 1, 1957 (Box-folder 19: 21)
- "Pismo k tovarishcham," Golos Sotsialdemokrata, 1910 (Box-folder 19: 22)
- Plekhanov, G., "K ukhodu Malinovskago," Edinstvo, 1914 (Box-folder 19: 23)
- "Popov Prague Conference," Krasnyi Arkhiv, p. 91-123, 1939 (Box-folder 19: 24)
- Possony, Stefan T., Lenin: The Compulsive Revolutionary, p. 154-162, 1968 (Box-folder 19: 25)
- "Pravda o dele myasoedova," Wovye Vedomosti, no. 85, 1918 (Box-folder 19: 26)
- "Velikaya voina," Spiridovich, vol. I, 1968 (Box-folder 19: 27)
- "Taratuta, polozhenie vo frantsii Moscow: gos izdat," Mockba, related research notes, 1919 (Box-folder 19: 28)
- "O tom, kto I kak sudil Malinovskogo," Russkoe Slovo, no. 125, 1917 June 4 (Box-folder 19: 29)
- "Ob ukhodu R. V. Malinovskago," Russkiya Vedomosti, no. 108, 1914 May 11 (Box-folder 19: 30)
- Olminsky, M., "O provokatore chernomazove," Mockba, 1926 (Box-folder 19: 31)
- Olminsky, M., "O provokatore chernomazove," Pravda, no. 8, p. 2, 1917 March 14 (Box-folder 19: 32)
- Olminsky, M., "O t Lenine," Sotsial Demokrat, no. 65, p. 1-2, 1917 May 28 (Box-folder 19: 33)
- "Otkaz ot deputatskikh polnomochii S. D. Malinovskago," Ruskie Vedomosti, no. 106, 1914 May 9 (Box-folder 19: 34)
- "Otstavka Malinovskago," Russkaya Vedomosti, no. 109, 1914 May 13 (Box-folder 19: 35)
- "Testimony of A. A. Makarov on April 14, 1917," Padenie, vol. II, 1925 (Box-folder 19: 36)
- "Testimony of A. T. Vasilev to the Extraordinary Investigatory Commission," Padenie, vol. I, 1925 (Box-folder 19: 37)
- "Vissarionov Testimony," Padenie, typed excerpts, 1917 May 24 (Box-folder 19: 38)
- "Sobraniya sobranie chlenov v pomeshchenii," Edinstvo, no. 17, 1910 April 29 (Box-folder 19: 39)
- Spravochnik, Duma, miscellaneous, 1913-1914 (Box-folder 19: 40)
- "Elegalnaya rabota bolshevistskoi fraktsii I. V., gosudarstvennoi dumy, po dokumentam departamenta politsii," Krasnyi Arkhiv, 1936 (Box-folder 19: 41)
- "Neskolko dokumentov o M.S. ol'minksom iz zhandarmskikh arkhivov," Krasnyi Arkhiv, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 42)
- Nomad, M., Apostles of Revolution, p. 342-343, 1961 (Box-folder 19: 43)
- "O klebetnik zaslavskom," Pravda, no. 81, 1917 June 27 (Box-folder 19: 44)
- "O provokatsii i provokatorakh," Pravda, no. 67, 1917 May 27 (Box-folder 19: 45)
- Romanov, A. F., "Russkogo ochaga," Russkaia Letopis, p. 1-38, 1922 (Box-folder 19: 46)
- "E. F. Rozmirovich," Pravda, p. 4, 1953 September 1 (Box-folder 19: 47)
- "Entsiklopedichesky slovar russkogo bibliograficheskago," Mockba, undated (Box-folder 19: 48)
- Shub, D., Lenin, 1968 August 13 (Box-folder 19: 49)
- "Sledstvie po delu Malinovskago," Pravda, no. 73, 1917 June 17 (Box-folder 19: 50)
- Nicolai, The German Secret Service, 1968 (Box-folder 19: 51)
- "V chrezvychainnoi sledstvennei hommissii," Dyen, no. 82, 1917 June 11 (Box-folder 20: 1)
- "V. I. Lenin V. A. Karpinskomu v zhenevu", Leninsky Sbornik XI, 1931 (Box-folder 20: 2)
- "Vokrug istpartovskoi raboty," Proletarskaya Revoliutsiya, no. 4, 1928 (Box-folder 20: 3)
- Preobrazhensky, E., "Valentina nikolaevna lobova," Proletarskaya Revolyutsiya, no. 7, 1924 (Box-folder 20: 4)
- "Tsiavlovoxii," Mockba, 1918 (Box-folder 20: 5)
- "V. I. Lenin - G. L. Shklovskomu," Leninsky Sbornik, vol. XIII, 1930 (Box-folder 20: 6)
- "V. N. bibliografiya o zubatovskikh soyuzakh, legalnom rabochem dvizhenie, gapone i 9-om yanvarya," Krasnaya Letopis, no. 1, 1922 (Box-folder 20: 7)
- "Sudba dvoinogo predatelya," Edinstvo, no. 1, 1917 March 29 (Box-folder 20: 8)
- Gerard, W., Lenine, p. 215-216, 1971 (Box-folder 20: 9)
- Wilcox, E. H., Russia's Ruin, excerpts, 1919 (Box-folder 20: 10)
- Wolfe, B., "Lenin and Malinovsky," Russian Review, vol. 5, 1945 (Box-folder 20: 11)
- Zviagintsev, E. A., "Provokatory i podstrekatlli," Zadruga, Petrograd, 1918 (Box-folder 20: 12)
- "Pravlenie," Edinstvo, no. 12, 1909 December 21 (Box-folder 20: 13)
- "Privet metallistam," Metallist, no. 3 (27), p. 1-3, 1913 June 15 (Box-folder 20: 14)
- "Provokator Malinovskago pered tribunalom," Kraznaya Gazeta, [utrennii vyp., no. 237], 1918 November 6 (Box-folder 20: 15)
- "The Provocateur Nikolai of the Gold Glasses," Byloe, no. 1 (35), 1926 (Box-folder 20: 16)
- "Provokator, zhitomipsky," Pravda, no. 84, 1917 June 30 (Box-folder 20: 17)
- "Provokatsiya i kommentsiya" Dyen, no. 89, 1917 June 20 (Box-folder 20: 18)
- Pyatnitsky, Zapiski Bolshevika, excerpts, 1968 (Box-folder 20: 19)
- P. M., "Iz zhizni," Edinstvo, no. 8, 1909 August 10 (Box-folder 20: 20)
- P. M., "Gosudarstvennaya Duma", Metallist, no. 11 (35), 1913 November 16 (Box-folder 20: 21)
- "Razsledovanie dela Malinovskago," Edinstvo, no. 66, 1917 June 16 (Box-folder 20: 22)
- "Razyarennye klebetniki," Edinstvo, no. 51, 1913 May 30 (Box-folder 20: 23)
- "Rech kerenskago," Edinstvo, no. 57, 1917 June 6 (Box-folder 20: 24)
- Zhitomirsky, Lobov, Malinovsky, prints and negatives, part 1, undated (Box-folder 20: 25)
- Zhitomirsky, Lobov, Malinovsky, prints and negatives, part 2, undated (Box-folder 20: 26)
- Zhitomirsky, Lobov, Malinovsky, prints and negatives, part 3, undated (Box-folder 20: 27)
- Miscellaneous, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 20: 28)
  Includes: correspondence from H. Montgomery Hyde and Crocker International Bank employees; two publications from the National Foreign Assessment Center and Vivian Gornick; and article clippings from the New York Times, Esquire, San Francisco Chronicle, The Register, TIME and National Enquirer. Article subjects include espionage, international policy, the Soviet Union and the CIA.
- Assorted articles, 1981 (Box-folder 20: 29)
- Assorted articles, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 20: 30)
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1951
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Available as PDF files. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder by date of creation.
  - Records released in 2010, 1951 (Reading room work station)